Integrate Lessons Learned
Welcome back to this session on value creation.
Now, the last step.
I've got to integrate my lessons learned. I just standardize my success factors.
I’ve got to integrate my lessons learned.
To do that, let's take a look at those three keywords
integrate lessons
learned.
Now, what does that word mean, learned?
Notice I always like to start with the last word, work my way back up.
What does that mean, learned? Well what comes out of learning?
I guess, what I know. I can't know something without learning it.
I got to learn it either from direct experience or book learning.
Now, we talk about a lesson.
That lesson can be out of a book or that lesson can be by experience.
You know, in the case of our dog, that's kind of experiential there.
When I hear that dog out my bedroom window barking and growling
and chewing up that newspaper. That’s not out of a book, that's experience.
Yeah. Out of a book is things like equations. You know, you heard book smart, street smart.
Experience is street smart. Either way, I get knowledge out of that.
Now, what does the word integrate mean? That means very simple, to mix in.
To blend it all together, to integrate it, means to put it into
the contents of other things I do in my life.
My philosophy of life and so on.
Well, as I go through here and look at these success factors that I’ve standardized on.
And I look at this whole process that I've been through.
Well, when you go through a process, you get certain lessons that come out of it. Hey, hey.
Some do's and some don’ts. And there are musts.
There are must do's and there are must don’ts. That simple.
Definitely, don't do that. And definitely, do do this.
So, you get those do’s and don'ts from going through this process.
If you do this over and over and over, you get some universal dos and don’ts.
Like don’t ever put your hand in the fire, you know that's like a universal don’t.
Whether that's on the kitchen burner or the campsite fire.
Don't ever put your hand in it. That's a universal don't.
So, when I look at this idea of integrating lessons learned.
I want to go mix those. Bring those lessons that I learned
from repeated cycles of doing this, back into the fabric of my life.
I want those lessons to govern my future direction in everything I do.
Now, by doing all of that. By progressively going through
the specific steps. By doing that.
I'm able to bring better value to my life.
To anything I do. Whether that's my personal life, or whether that's my professional life.
That strategy
and those fundamental tools. That way of thinking.
That mental set of filters
that allows me to take all the things in my life and filter them down.
Like a sweet drop fallen out of that filter.
That's a part of the vital few success factors and lessons,
and run them back in my life. That's how I create value.
Thank You for choosing SSMI.